{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The concept of putting microbes to help clean up the environment is called", "opta": "pasteurization", "optb": "bioremediation", "optc": "fermentation", "optd": "biolistics", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not employed as an oxidation method?", "opta": "Oxidation ponds", "optb": "Trickling filters", "optc": "Contact aerators", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The filtering medium of trickling filters is coated with microbial flora, known as", "opta": "zoological film", "optb": "geological film", "optc": "zooglocal film", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Some cyanobacteria produce potent neurotoxins that, if ingested, will kill humans. These cyanobacteria are most likely to contaminate", "opta": "water rich in organic carbon wastes but poor in phosphate", "optb": "water that are anoxic", "optc": "water rich in phosphate wastes but poor in organic carbon", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The biogas production process takes place at the temperature", "opta": "lesser than 25\u00b0C", "optb": "25-40\u00b0C", "optc": "45-60\u00b0C", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Advanced treatment is generally used to treat waste water to", "opta": "remove coarse solids", "optb": "remove settleable solids", "optc": "reduce BOD", "optd": "remove additional objectionable substances", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Treatment of municipal water supplies is based upon", "opta": "coagulation, filtration, chlorination", "optb": "chlorination, filtration, coagulation", "optc": "filtration, coagulation, chlorination", "optd": "coagulation, chlorination, filtration", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is an anaerobic digester?", "opta": "New diet drink", "optb": "Microbe that eats hazardous waste", "optc": "Method to convert agricultural waste into a biogas", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The use of microbes to break down synthetic waste products such as polychlorinated biphenyls is called", "opta": "bioinformatics", "optb": "biolistics", "optc": "biotechnology", "optd": "bioremediation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Activated sludge contains large number of", "opta": "bacteria", "optb": "yeasts and molds", "optc": "protozoa", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Iron bacteria can produce", "opta": "slime", "optb": "undesirable odors and tastes", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "extreme acidity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biomass", "opta": "provides the U.S. with about 50% of its energy", "optb": "consists largely of wood, animal, and human waste", "optc": "is unlikely to be a major source of energy globally", "optd": "offers the consumer high quality energy with low environmental impact", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Composting is one of the oldest forms of disposal of waste. It is the natural process of decomposition of organic waste that yields manure or compost. One of the following is added to the compost to get better results?", "opta": "Ants", "optb": "Bugs", "optc": "Snakes", "optd": "Worms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a form of biomass energy?", "opta": "Incineration of solid waste", "optb": "Composting to produce methane", "optc": "Ethanol and methanol production for auto fuel", "optd": "Photovoltaic production of hydrogen", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is not correct?", "opta": "The use of 25-40\u00b0C temperatures allows the biogas production to be more stable", "optb": "The use of 25-40\u00b0C temperatures does not destroy potentially harmful bacteria", "optc": "The use of 25-40\u00b0C temperatures destroys potentially harmful bacteria", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Oxidation ponds are shallow ponds, generally designed at the depth of", "opta": "2 to 40 feet", "optb": "4 to 6 feet", "optc": "1 to 3 feet", "optd": "5 to 8 feet", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is generally not referred to the sewerage system?", "opta": "Sanitary sewers", "optb": "Storm sewers", "optc": "Combined sewers", "optd": "Solid sewers", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The magnitude of BOD of wastewater is related to", "opta": "bacterial count", "optb": "amount of organic material", "optc": "amount of inorganic material", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A dense bacterial population caught in a tangled web of fibers sticking to a surface describes", "opta": "coagulation", "optb": "a biodisc", "optc": "a biofilm", "optd": "the membrane filter technique", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Biogas production is", "opta": "a temperature-dependent process", "optb": "a temperature independent process", "optc": "an oxygen dependent process", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The acetate-utilizing methanogens are responsible for", "opta": "20% of methane produced in a biogas reactor", "optb": "50% of methane produced in a biogas reactor", "optc": "70% of methane produced in a biogas reactor", "optd": "85% of methane produced in a biogas reactor", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is responsible for the corrosion problem?", "opta": "Iron bacteria", "optb": "Sulfur bacteria", "optc": "Slime forming bacteria", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water testing relies on the detection of certain indicator organisms known as", "opta": "acid-fast bacteria", "optb": "bacteroids", "optc": "coliforms", "optd": "dinoflagellates", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The death of a river by environmental pollutants ultimately results from", "opta": "the overpopulation of algae", "optb": "the overabundance of toxic proteins", "optc": "the depletion of oxygen", "optd": "the buildup of sediment on the river bottom", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}